<?xml version="1.0"?>
<metadata xml:lang="en"><idinfo><keywords><theme><themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt><themekey>biota</themekey><themekey>boundaries</themekey><themekey>environment</themekey><themekey>location</themekey><themekey>oceans</themekey><themekey>planningCadastre</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>EPA GIS Keyword Thesaurus</themekt><themekey>Biology</themekey><themekey>Compliance</themekey><themekey>Conservation</themekey><themekey>Ecology</themekey><themekey>Ecosystem</themekey><themekey>Environment</themekey><themekey>Human</themekey><themekey>Management</themekey><themekey>Marine</themekey><themekey>Monitoring</themekey><themekey>Natural Resources</themekey><themekey>Permits</themekey><themekey>Regulatory</themekey><themekey>Water</themekey></theme><place><placekt>None</placekt><placekey>Atlantic Ocean</placekey><placekey>Georges Bank</placekey><placekey>Greater Atlantic Region</placekey><placekey>Mid-Atlantic</placekey><placekey>New England</placekey><placekey>Southern New England</placekey><placekey>United States</placekey><placekey>US EEZ</placekey><placekey>US Exclusive Economic Zone</placekey><placekey>Oceanographer Canyon</placekey><placekey>Gilbert Canyon</placekey><placekey>Lydonia Canyon</placekey><placekey>Bear Seamount</placekey><placekey>Physalia Seamount</placekey><placekey>Retriever Seamount</placekey><placekey>Mytilus Seamount</placekey></place><theme><themekt>GARFO Keywords</themekt><themekey>American Lobster</themekey><themekey>Atlantic</themekey><themekey>Atlantic Deep-Sea Red Crab</themekey><themekey>Atlantic Mackerel, Squid, and Butterfish</themekey><themekey>Atlantic Sea Scallop</themekey><themekey>EEZ</themekey><themekey>Endangered Species Act</themekey><themekey>ESA</themekey><themekey>Exclusive Economic Zone</themekey><themekey>GARFO</themekey><themekey>Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office</themekey><themekey>Magnuson-Stevens Act</themekey><themekey>Marine Mammal Protection Act</themekey><themekey>MMPA</themekey><themekey>Monkfish</themekey><themekey>MSA</themekey><themekey>National Marine Fisheries Service</themekey><themekey>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</themekey><themekey>NEFMC</themekey><themekey>New England Fishery Management Council</themekey><themekey>NMFS</themekey><themekey>NOAA</themekey><themekey>Small Mesh Multispecies</themekey><themekey>Summer Flounder, Scup, and Black Sea Bass</themekey><themekey>US EEZ</themekey><themekey>Canyon</themekey><themekey>Antiquities Act</themekey><themekey>Deep Sea Canyons</themekey><themekey>Marine National Monument</themekey><themekey>National Wildlife Refuge System</themekey><themekey>National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act</themekey><themekey>Northeast Canyons and Seamounts Marine National Monument</themekey><themekey>NWRS</themekey><themekey>NWRSAA</themekey><themekey>Refuges</themekey><themekey>Refuge Recreation Act</themekey><themekey>RRA</themekey><themekey>Seamount</themekey><themekey>U.S. Department of Commerce</themekey><themekey>U.S. Department of the Interior</themekey><themekey>U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service</themekey><themekey>USFWS</themekey></theme></keywords><citation><citeinfo><origin>NOAA Fisheries Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office</origin><title>Northeast Canyons and Seamounts Marine National Monument</title><pubinfo><publish>NOAA National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS) - Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office (GARFO)</publish><pubplace>Gloucester, MA</pubplace></pubinfo><pubdate>20161202</pubdate><onlink>http://www.greateratlantic.fisheries.noaa.gov/gis</onlink><onlink>http://www.greateratlantic.fisheries.noaa.gov/</onlink></citeinfo></citation><timeperd><current>Publication date</current><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20161202</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>As needed</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-69</westbc><eastbc>-65</eastbc><northbc>41</northbc><southbc>37</southbc></bounding></spdom><accconst>None.</accconst><useconst>*** Attribution *** Whenever NMFS material is reproduced and re-disseminated, we request that users attribute the material appropriately.  Pursuant to 17 U.S.C. 403, parties who produce copyrighted works consisting predominantly of material created by the Federal Government are encouraged to provide notice with such work(s) identifying the U.S. Government material incorporated and stating that such material is not subject to copyright protection. Please cite Regulated Area datasets as follows:  NOAA Fisheries Service. Northeast Canyons and Seamounts Marine National Monument Boundaries. [Shapefile]. Gloucester, MA: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office (GARFO) [producer] 14 November 2016. http://www.greateratlantic.fisheries.noaa.gov/gis.  *** No Warranty*** The user assumes the entire risk related to its use of these data. NMFS is providing these data "as is," and NMFS disclaims any and all warranties, whether express or implied, including (without limitation) any implied warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose. No warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the accuracy or utility of the data on any other system or for general or scientific purposes, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. It is strongly recommended that careful attention be paid to the contents of the metadata file associated with these data to evaluate dataset limitations, restrictions or intended use.  In no event will NMFS be liable to you or to any third party for any direct, indirect, incidental, consequential, special or exemplary damages or lost profit resulting from any use or misuse of this data.  *** Proper Usage *** The information on government servers are in the public domain, unless specifically annotated otherwise, and may be used freely by the public. Before using information obtained from this server, special attention should be given to the date and time of the data and products being displayed. This information shall not be modified in content and then presented as official government material.  This dataset was created to depict the boundaries of the Marine National Monument only.  The dataset should not be used for a legal definition.  The dataset should not be used to infer information regarding the existence or details of other marine features or resources, including, but not limited to, navigable waters, coastlines, bathymetry, submerged features, or man-made structures.  Users assume responsibility for determining the appropriate use of this dataset.  *** Not the Legal Definition *** This Geographic Information System (GIS) dataset is not the legal definition of the Regulated Area. The description published in the U.S. Code of Federal Regulations is the only legal definition. This dataset and metadata document provide a broad overview of a subset of applicable fishing regulations, restrictions and requirements; it is not a substitute for the actual regulations. Users are encouraged to read the applicable regulations in conjunction with use of this dataset.    *** Temporal Considerations *** Boundary definitions are subject to change or modification.  Published datasets may represent historic, current, or future boundaries.  When changes to regulations affect this dataset, it will be archived and replaced by an updated version as soon as feasible.  Approved boundaries may also be published prior to their effective date.  It is the user’s responsibility to ensure the applicable boundaries are being used.    *** Base Layers *** The accuracy of this dataset is dependent upon the accuracy and resolution of the datasets (e.g., shoreline, bathymetry, shared administrative boundaries) used in the creation process. Source datasets used are specified in the metadata.  These data sources were selected for their suitability to a broad audience, and may not be suitable for specific uses requiring higher-resolution information.</useconst><descript><abstract>This dataset depicts the boundaries of the Northeast Canyons and Seamounts Marine National Monument in ESRI shapefile format for the NOAA Fisheries Service’s Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office (GARFO).  This shapefile includes boundaries for the following Regulated Areas:
 - Northeast Canyons and Seamounts Marine National Monument Canyon Unit
 - Northeast Canyons and Seamounts Marine National Monument Seamount Unit

Because GIS projection and topology functions can change or generalize coordinates, these GIS files are considered to be approximate representations and are NOT an OFFICIAL record for the exact regulated area boundaries.  For information on the official legal definition refer to the Use Constraints metadata section.</abstract><purpose>This dataset was created to depict the boundaries of this marine national monument only.  For information on the proper use of the dataset refer to the Use Constraints metadata section.

On September 15, 2016, President Obama designated the first marine national monument in the Atlantic Ocean, the Northeast Canyons and Seamounts Marine National Monument, using his authority under the Antiquities Act of 1906.

The monument includes two distinct areas.  The Canyon Unit covers Oceanographer, Gilbert, and Lydonia Canyons. The Seamount Unit covers Bear, Physalia, Retriever, and Mytilus Seamounts. These are located about 130 miles east-southeast of Cape Cod, and cover a total area of more than 4,900 square miles, about the size of Connecticut, or slightly larger than Yellowstone National Park. 

From the Presidential Proclamation:
"The Secretaries of Commerce and the Interior (Secretaries) shall share management responsibility for the monument. The Secretary of Commerce, through the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), and in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall have responsibility for management of activities and species within the monument under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act, the Endangered Species Act (for species regulated by NOAA), the Marine Mammal Protection Act, and any other applicable Department of Commerce legal authorities. The Secretary of the Interior, through the United States Fish and Wildlife Service (FWS), and in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, shall have responsibility for management of activities and species within the monument under its applicable legal authorities, including the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act, the Refuge Recreation Act, and the Endangered Species Act (for species regulated by FWS), and Public Law 98-532 and Executive Order 6166 of June 10, 1933."</purpose></descript><secinfo><secsys>FIPS Pub 199</secsys><secclass>public</secclass><sechandl>Standard Technical Controls</sechandl></secinfo><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>NOAA Fisheries Service Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office, GIS Committee</cntorg><cntper>Dean-Lorenz Szumylo</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>55 Great Republic Drive</address><city>Gloucester</city><state>MA</state><postal>01930</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>978-282-8479</cntvoice><cntfax>978-281-9333</cntfax><cntemail>dean.szumylo@noaa.gov</cntemail><cntinst>http://www.greateratlantic.fisheries.noaa.gov/</cntinst></cntinfo></ptcontac></idinfo><dataqual><logic>Check Geometry test has been performed in ArcGIS.</logic><complete>Features represented are valid.  No geometry problems were detected.</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>Data were collected using methods that are accurate to within 1 meter (EPA National Geospatial Data Policy [NGDP] Accuracy Tier 1). For more information, please see EPA's NGDP at http://epa.gov/geospatial/policies.html</horizpar></horizpa></posacc><lineage><procstep><procdate>2013</procdate><procdesc>[Template Generation] Many NMFS Regulated Areas in Northeast and Mid-Atlantic Waters (Regulated Areas) share boundaries that are partially coincident with any combination of the following: 1) the U.S. Atlantic coastline; 2) the Submerged Lands Act boundary; 3) the U.S.-Canada Maritime Boundary in the Gulf of Maine; 4) the outward extent of the U.S. Exclusive Economic Zone (a.k.a. the "200-nautical mile line"). To standardize Regulated Area features sharing these boundaries, published shapefiles of the shared administrative boundaries were obtained from the authoritative agencies.  A shoreline was selected that was suitable for general mapping purposes, freely and publicly available, of medium-resolution, and covering the extent of the U.S..  When necessary, the boundaries were transformed to NAD83. A series of template polygon shapefiles were then generated, using these authoritative boundaries as the outward extents of the polygon.  All templates were generated in NAD83 geographic coordinate system.  The templates created are: 1) Coast-to-EEZ: bounded by the coastline, the U.S.-Canada Maritime Boundary, the U.S. EEZ, and 81°W longitude off the southern extent of Florida (an arbitrary cut-off for the Atlantic); 2) Coast-to-SLA: bounded by the coastline, the U.S.-Canada Maritime Boundary, the Submerged Lands Act boundary, and 81°W longitude off the southern extent of Florida; 3) SLA-to-EEZ: bounded by the Submerged Lands Act boundary, the U.S.-Canada Maritime Boundary, the U.S. EEZ, and 81°W longitude off the southern extent of Florida.  These templates were subsequently copied and edited, as needed by the Regulated Area spatial definitions.</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>2016</procdate><procdesc>[Get Definition Text] The spatial definition for the Monument was copied from the Press Release.</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>2016</procdate><procdesc>[Features From Templates] After determining that the bounding coordinates are connected following rhumb lines, the boundaries were drawn in an empty polyline shapefile (NAD83 geographic coordinate system) using the "Loxodrome" line type in the "Construct Geodetic" tool in ArcGIS 10. To generate the Monument boundary in ArcGIS, a copy of the Coast-to-EEZ template polygon was split by tracing this polyline boundary file. When the spatial definition specified that points were connected following the EEZ, the coinciding outward extent of the template polygon was used.  After all points were appropriately connected, any portions of the template outside the defined Monument areas were discarded.</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>2016</procdate><procdesc>[Add Attributes] An attribute schema was applied to the shapefile, and the fields were defined.</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>2016</procdate><procdesc>[Area Calculation] The shapefile was projected into a customized "USA_Contiguous_Albers_Equal_Area_Conic_USGS_version" projected coordinate system.  The coordinate system was modified to focus on the offshore region of the Monument.  Coordinate System modifications include adjusting projection parameters as follows:  False_Easting: 0.0; False_Northing: 0.0; Central_Meridian: -67.0775; Standard_Parallel_1: 38.865; Standard_Parallel_2: 40.6; Latitude_Of_Origin: 39.7325.  In the Equal Area shapefile, each feature's area was calculated in square miles and square kilometers.  These values were copied back to the un-projected NAD83 version of the shapefile.  Conversions to square nautical miles were calculated outside of GIS.</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>2016</procdate><procdesc>[Policy Review] The Monument spatial definition, shapefile geometry and attribute values were reviewed with policy staff to verify that the shapefile accurately depicted and described the intended boundaries.</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>2016</procdate><procdesc>[Check Geometry] The ESRI ArcGIS Check Geometry tool was run on the shapefile to identify any geometry problems.  If problems were encountered, they were reviewed and corrected.</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>2016</procdate><procdesc>[Metadata] A GARFO Regulated Area shapefile metadata template was developed using the EPA Metadata Editor v3.2.  This template was applied and customized to reflect the specific characteristics of the given shapefile.  The metadata was validated for FGDC CSDGM compliance.</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>2016</procdate><procdesc>[Final Review] The shapefile was reviewed by members of the GARFO GIS Committee, policy experts from the GARFO Division responsible for the Regulated Area, and General Counsel, according to the GARFO GIS Data Distribution Policy. The shapefile was then shared with colleagues at the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service for review by their agency.  Comments and feedback were incorporated into the data as necessary.</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>20161202</procdate><procdesc>[Publication] The shapefile, with accompanying metadata, was uploaded for public download on the NOAA NMFS GARFO GIS website.</procdesc></procstep><srcinfo><typesrc>digital download (ESRI shapefile)</typesrc><srccitea>US EEZ</srccitea><srccontr>This source  marine boundary was used to generate template shapefiles, which were copied and used when Regulatory Area boundaries followed portions of the US Exclusive Economic Zone.</srccontr><srctime><srccurr>publication date</srccurr><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20110501</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo></srctime><srccite><citeinfo><origin>Department of Commerce (DOC), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS)</origin><title>USMaritimeLimitsNBoundaries</title><edition>1</edition><geoform>vector digital data</geoform><pubdate>20110501</pubdate><pubinfo><publish>NOAA's Ocean Service, Office of Coast Survey (OCS)</publish><pubplace>Silver Spring, MD</pubplace></pubinfo><onlink>http://www.nauticalcharts.noaa.gov/csdl/mbound.htm</onlink></citeinfo></srccite></srcinfo><srcinfo><typesrc>online</typesrc><srccitea>Press Release</srccitea><srccontr>This document identifies the bounding coordinates of the monument.</srccontr><srctime><srccurr>publication date</srccurr><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20160915</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo></srctime><srccite><citeinfo><origin>U.S. Department of the Interior</origin><title>Secretaries Pritzker, Jewell Applaud President’s Designation of Northeast Canyons and Seamounts Marine National Monument</title><geoform>map</geoform><othercit>Citation is a joint Press Release issued by U.S. Secretary of Commerce Penny Pritzker and U.S. Secretary of the Interior Sally Jewell, citing President Obama's designation of the Northeast Canyons and Seamounts Marine National Monument. Online links point to static map graphics containing the bounding coordinates used to make this file.  Monument boundaries will be codified in the Code of Federal Regulations (CFR) at a later date.  At that point the CFR will represent the legal boundary definition.</othercit><pubdate>20160915</pubdate><pubinfo><publish>U.S. Department of the Interior</publish><pubplace>Washington, DC</pubplace></pubinfo><onlink>https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/secretaries-pritzker-jewell-applaud-presidents-designation-northeast-canyons-and</onlink><onlink>https://www.doi.gov/sites/doi.gov/files/uploads/northeastcanyonsandseamountsmnm_600.pdf</onlink><onlink>https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/09/15/presidential-proclamation-northeast-canyons-and-seamounts-marine</onlink><onlink>https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/09/15/fact-sheet-president-obama-continue-global-leadership-combatting-climate</onlink><onlink>http://www.noaa.gov/news/first-marine-national-monument-created-in-atlantic</onlink></citeinfo></srccite></srcinfo></lineage></dataqual><spref><horizsys><geograph><latres>0.000001</latres><longres>0.000001</longres><geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit></geograph><geodetic><horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn><ellips>Geodetic Reference System 1980</ellips><semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis><denflat>298.257222</denflat></geodetic></horizsys></spref><eainfo><detailed><enttyp><enttypl>Regulated Area</enttypl><enttypd>NMFS Regulated Areas in Northeast and Mid-Atlantic Waters</enttypd><enttypds>GARFO</enttypds></enttyp><attr><attrlabl>FID</attrlabl><attrdef>Internal feature number</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>System-generated internal feature number</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl><attrdef>Feature geometry</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Coordinate geometry</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>GARFO_ID</attrlabl><attrdef>A unique identifier used to identify and track this feature; a new GARFO_ID is generated for each version of a Regulated Area (i.e. whenever boundaries or attributes are changed, edited or updated)</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>System-generated number</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>AREANAME</attrlabl><attrdef>Official name of the Regulated Area, usually the area name as printed in the CFR</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>COMMNAME</attrlabl><attrdef>Most commonly used name.  May be identical to AREANAME, an abbreviation of AREANAME, or a different name altogether.</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>AREAGROUP</attrlabl><attrdef>Specifies if the Regulated Area is part of a group of related areas</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>DESCRIBE</attrlabl><attrdef>A brief description of the purpose of the Regulated Area</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text description</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CFRTITLE</attrlabl><attrdef>CFR Title citation where the Regulated Area is legally defined</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CFRPT</attrlabl><attrdef>CFR Part citation where the Regulated Area is legally defined</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text citation</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CFRPTTXT</attrlabl><attrdef>CFR Part citation header text</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CFRSUB</attrlabl><attrdef>CFR Subpart citation where the Regulated Area is legally defined</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text citation</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CFRSUBTXT</attrlabl><attrdef>CFR Subpart citation header text</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CFRSXN</attrlabl><attrdef>CFR Section citation where the Regulated Area is legally defined</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text citation</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CFRSXNTXT</attrlabl><attrdef>CFR Section citation header text</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CFRPARA</attrlabl><attrdef>CFR Paragraph citation where the Regulated Area is legally defined</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text citation</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CFRPARATXT</attrlabl><attrdef>CFR Paragraph citation header text</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>FRCITE</attrlabl><attrdef>Federal Register citation of original Regulated Area spatial definition, or last modification to the spatial definition, whichever is most recent.  Refers to SPATIAL DEFINITION ONLY.  Subsequent FR notices may have modified the requirements affecting waters within or outside this Regulated Area.</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>FRDATE</attrlabl><attrdef>Federal Register citation date of original Regulated Area spatial definition, or the last modification to the spatial definition, whichever is most recent.  Refers to SPATIAL DEFINITION ONLY.  Subsequent FR notices may have modified the requirements affecting waters within or outside this Regulated Area.</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Date</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>EFFECTDATE</attrlabl><attrdef>Date Regulated Area officially became law, or most recent modification</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Date</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>SOURCE</attrlabl><attrdef>If Regulated Area is defined in the CFR, this is the citation for the Amendment/Framework/etc. that established the area.  If the Regulated Area is not defined in the CFR, this is the alternative source citation establishing the Regulated Area.</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text citation</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>RECURST</attrlabl><attrdef>Annually recurring date Regulated Area becomes active</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Date</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>RECUREND</attrlabl><attrdef>Annually recurring date Regulated Area becomes inactive</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Date</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>GISAUTHOR</attrlabl><attrdef>Name of the NOAA staff person who created the GIS feature</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CREATED</attrlabl><attrdef>Creation date of the GIS feature</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Date</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>AREANOTES</attrlabl><attrdef>Miscellaneous notes regarding the Regulated Area or feature</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text description</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>SQMI</attrlabl><attrdef>The feature area in square miles.</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Coordinate geometry</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>SQNMI</attrlabl><attrdef>The feature area in square nautical miles.</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Coordinate geometry</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>SQKM</attrlabl><attrdef>The feature area in square kilometers</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Coordinate geometry</udom></attrdomv></attr></detailed><overview><eaover>Entity Attributes provide reference information for the Regulated Areas represented.  Attributes provide citations for the legal spatial definition and originating documents, and currentness information for each area.</eaover><eadetcit>FILEDS_Map.xlsx fully describes the Attribute Schema used for regulated area GIS data sets.  To access this document, see the Contact Information.</eadetcit></overview></eainfo><distinfo><resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc><distliab>The user assumes the entire risk related to use of these data. NMFS is providing these data "as is," and NMFS disclaims any and all warranties, whether express or implied, including (without limitation) any implied warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose. No warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the accuracy or utility of the data on any other system or for general or scientific purposes, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. It is strongly recommended that careful attention be paid to the contents of the metadata file associated with these data to evaluate dataset limitations, restrictions or intended use.  In no event will NMFS be liable to you or to any third party for any direct, indirect, incidental, consequential, special or exemplary damages, or lost profit resulting from any use or misuse of this data</distliab><distrib><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>NOAA Fisheries Service Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office, GIS Committee</cntorg><cntper>Dean-Lorenz Szumylo</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>55 Great Republic Drive</address><city>Gloucester</city><state>MA</state><postal>01930</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>978-282-8479</cntvoice><cntfax>978-281-9333</cntfax><cntemail>dean.szumylo@noaa.gov</cntemail><cntinst>http://www.greateratlantic.fisheries.noaa.gov/</cntinst></cntinfo></distrib></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20161202</metd><metfrd>20201202</metfrd><metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>NOAA Fisheries Service Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office, GIS Committee</cntorg><cntper>Dean-Lorenz Szumylo</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>55 Great Republic Drive</address><city>Gloucester</city><state>MA</state><postal>01930</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>978-282-8479</cntvoice><cntfax>978-281-9333</cntfax><cntemail>dean.szumylo@noaa.gov</cntemail><cntinst>http://www.greateratlantic.fisheries.noaa.gov/</cntinst></cntinfo></metc></metainfo><spdoinfo><direct>Vector</direct></spdoinfo></metadata>